junkyard CL podcast at what age do we
learn how to have better
conversation junkyard love podcast so
what I would love to do Wendy welcome
welcome to the show Welcome to the John
love podcast thank you again for doing
this um we have just briefly mentioned
your new podcast uh demystifying the
transgender journey I think is the name
of it correct me if I'm wrong but I
would love um the link to that is going
to be below anybody who wants to check
that out follow that but I would love a
little bit of a background bio on that
what what what is that what have you
been working on um tell us all about uni
podcast well Jacob thank you very much
for mentioning all of this I I believe
that I've start I I'm started on this
path in 2015 when I started Living my
authentic self I wound up talking with
my neighbors I talked with people I the
community I lived in um there was a
large gay population as well as
cisgender straight people and I wound up
talking with everybody about what it
means to be born
transgender
so by
2022 or so I started to get really
highly annoyed at all the out
there about people like myself all the
lies all the
misinformation uh the fostering fear and
everything else
I decided okay if there's a way I can
use my voice and all I'll put put
something out there opposite of that and
I'd kind of like to actually
inform a regular straight Society what
this is about those are the people that
I want to talk to so I got uh really
interested in fascinated with
podcasting uh when I moved to Rhode
Island I hired an agency the second day
I was in my apartment I hired an agency
to represent and promote me on podcast
interviews and that started my
podcasting in the fall of
2023 I met Lynn Murphy a cisgender woman
knew very little about the LGBT world
but was very fascinated with what it
meant to be born transgender and she
wanted to interview me for her podcast
and a and a book one thing led to
another we became friends we've recorded
a lot of video with me and we've
recorded other people as well and by the
spring of 2024 we did an agreement to
co-host a brand new podcast called
demystifying the transgender
Journey she's been like a sponge
absorbing everything I've told her
researching talking to other people as
well she's an accomplished author and
podcaster of on her own
rights and it's just been a an
incredible collaboration
and I've invited other transgender
people to join me in a community that
we're doing as well as the podcast but
the community is for straight and gay
cisgender people who may have
transgender people in their lives and a
lot of people in the transgender commun
Community I I understand this I don't
personally agree for me I'm open to
answering questions people have a lot of
people are not comfortable with that so
even if you're friends with somebody
your friend who's transgender may not be
open to having a conversation about what
their life is like how they feel a lot
of people feel that it's uh
kind of a thing where you are being
challenged to explain
yourself no matter how nice the person
is so one of the things that I like to
do with people is ask me anything you
want to don't worry about how you phrase
it if it's phrased in such a way that I
think is hurtful to another person or
might make might make them uncomfortable
or upset with you I'll explain how to
ask the question better and that's how
we learn to communicate with one
another we're we're regular people just
like anybody else right just a person
too exactly
so um the whole podcast the whole
Community everything is oriented
at now my mission is to humanize being
born transgender for the rest of soci
Society MH and in order to do that I'm
doing that with conversations with uh
speaking with people I've uh also added
this year I've added
Consulting my career in Tech I my last
18 years I was a consultant in
technology well I can be a consultant on
transgender too yeah yeah human
technology as well
exactly yeah so
I I love what I'm doing and I also love
uh coaching people and helping them
through their transitions at whatever
stage they're in a lot of us
are I had tremendous limiting
beliefs about what was possible for
me and they were formed in
childhood and all the way through my
teenage years I had told my parents that
I was a
girl at age
10 and that did not go well I was
threatened with being committed to a
psychiatric facility and fixed so I
formed all of these beliefs of course
when you're when you're
born that's when the doctor looks and
says it's a boy or it's a
girl well that's just the physical sex
period That's the genitals for sexual uh
reproduction has nothing to do with
gender gender is between the ears not
the
legs uh gender is formed in the frontal
cortex of the brain during the second
trimester of birth the sex uh sexual
orientation is also formed in the brain
in the amigdala of the brain in the
second
trimester and for most people those are
all totally congruent with what happened
to the body
physically for some of us myself
included I got a full dose of
female in the frontal cortex of my brain
I knew it was there by age three and
four I felt different I felt comfortable
with other little girls not with little
boys it was just that simple it's a
feeling and you hear or read or
whatever uh dysphoria people are
dysphoric um and all what that really is
is that's the in congruence between how
you feel how your mind feels about who
you really are
versus when you're born and the doctor
announces it's a boy or a girl the
socialization begins from that moment
from the parents the immediate family
the extended family it grows into the
school system and your friends and by
the time you're five six seven 8 years
old you
know you can't really Express what you
feel because of the socialization you've
experienced you know how bad it is that
the way people feel about it right uh
you can't be a girl you are born a boy
well that's just the physical
Anatomy it's not what's in your brain
it's not what how you were uh designed
before birth right right okay so what it
I I was I was thinking about this
because something something that you
said so so for one just to lay a little
groundwork before my question something
that you said that I really liked and it
was something I started this podcast
with something in similarity in mind is
that that you often just go you'll go to
you know a bar or a restaurant and just
sometimes sit down next to somebody and
strike up a conversation and uh just
kind of you know see see see where
they're at it with it you know and I can
imagine the beauty of the conversations
that must unfold um you know maybe some
clunky areas that you probably have to
tredge past but so so I was thinking
about you know what what I would like if
if I was not even you know thinking
about you but you sit next to me and
then suddenly I'm I'm in this you know
incredibly interesting conversation
about
transgenderism um transgenderism is a
word right yeah ISM yeah it can be yeah
okay well I I guess I'm making it a word
today it could be made up made up in my
world um but so okay so so I was
thinking like I have personally spent a
lot of time you know we've talked about
I really love meditation I really like
philosophy um even like deeper into
meditation if you've heard of adite the
vant um a lot of like reflection of the
self and what is the self and and who
all that fun interesting stuff so I've
spent a lot of time in that area but
even when I was younger I never really
it never really occurred to me of of
wondering who I am well am I a different
gender and so I was like so when I think
about you know myself and my uh what
does it mean to be a human what does it
mean to be you know just a person in the
world I
don't the gender part never occurs to me
and so as much as I think that I could
like relate with you when I have my own
versions of uh you know everybody has
questions who they are and what what is
all this whatever but you have this
other thing that I just I don't have the
experience with so I think my question
would be what what are the what are the
cories to you between like you know
everybody questions who am I what am I
doing here what's this all about who am
you know I was born to these parents I
feel this way they tell me I'm this way
all that stuff what is the difference
between like that and questioning your
gender how's that feel for you anyway
actually uh I really appreciate this
question a lot it
um for most people one of the reasons
they never question their gender and for
most people the word gender isn't even
really an active part of their vocab
vocabulary oh yeah uh because of that
you know stereo type of the doctor
checking the baby and announcing it's a
boy or a girl everybody uses the word
sex your sex is female your sex is
male while that applies to your physical
Anatomy it doesn't necessarily apply to
your gender for fortunately for most
people there is no in congruence between
the gender that was implanted in the
frontal cortex of their brain and their
physical being there's no in congruence
there they never question it so that's
one thing that I always tell people if
you've never looked in the mirror and
questioned your actual gender identity I
should have been a boy or I should have
been a girl if you've never done that I
don't expect you to fully understand
this and understand the depth of um the
distress that this brings on people
right um on the other
hand this is just a much more profound
life change than what anybody else would
go
through um packing up and changing
careers and moving across the country
that's a profound life
change and the only difference between
that and this is
just your physical presentation what
you're doing we go through the same
process of what are our thoughts about
this and what are the beliefs that we
have that are preventing us from
achieving that life change that we
either want or know we need to go
through that's one of the things that I
had to work on is shifting all of my
thoughts and emotions which I formed in
childhood and teenage years that kept me
safe because I couldn't tell people
about this I found out when I told my
parents it was a very bad
thing so now I have all these beliefs
you know you can't do this
um
it's a a very impactful thing you wind
up I found I depressed huge parts of my
personality
too I couldn't be social with people I
had this secret I was hiding
right and the way I got through all of
this my first therapy
appointment uh from my first through my
third my therapist challenged every one
of my thoughts every one of my
beliefs in
myself and
I started learning how to rewrite the
stories we tell ourselves the same
thoughts and stories every day 90% of
the time they're the same from day to
day they become locked in rockard
beliefs so in order to make this
transition and by the way I hadn't I
hadn't crossdressed in 35 years at the
time of my first therapy appointment in
January of 2015 I hadn't talked to
another human being about how I feel in
4 and a half
decades
wow all that repression was making me
physically sick I couldn't imagine yeah
that must been so heavy yeah I I was 70
lounds heavier than I am now my blood
work was
horrible and I was type two diabetic
three years of living authentically and
completely changing my
life all that one away my blood work
comes back perfect all the time my
primary care doctor was freaking out
over it and said to me what do you
attribute this to and I said I'm happy
yeah
truth Liv truth time exactly I'm not
hiding anything yeah and I'm not
repressing anymore with all those hor
thoughts and those emotions that are
associated with those thoughts they'll
kill
you we we produce chemicals in our
bodies uh neuropeptides from the brain
chemicals from different organs of the
body and that's how the human mind
communicates with the body how we feel
what we're thinking whether or not we're
in anxiety or depression or fear or
survival mode or whatever it is or
complete and total
joy and that is communicated to our
bodies physically Through Chemistry and
all of the drugs we produce we're the
best drug dealers going they're highly
addicted all
holding all holding and we can get
totally addicted to depression anxiety
it becomes a way of life and that's who
we are
yeah
and I wouldn't wish being born
transgender on my worst
enemy that is how intense this this
is uh we have all kinds of ways of
distracting
ourselves um I distracted myself with my
tech
work um technology it was normal to have
a 10 12 14-hour day work
week so okay that's a distraction and I
enjoyed the computers and all of that
stuff it was
fun but um uh I just
really can't begin to tell you how
profound of a life change this really is
for people yeah but it doesn't have to
be that difficult when I transitioned I
did not know any other transgender
people there's really we only a really
small percentage of the population all
this BS out there about us is about a
little over 1% of the
population yeah I feel like a lot of uh
I don't want to dive to into like you
know what the news networks are saying
and stuff but I feel like they make it
sound like there's like boogie man out
there like oh be careful you know watch
out there's all these transgender people
who are trying to lie to your kids
whatever it's it's so silly and they're
they're overlooking your humanity and
it's just it's it's really a boring take
to be honest but um it's something that
we're all dealing with so I'm glad that
you are here speaking your truth and
sharing with people you know it's um one
of the things that I learned once I
started uh deconstructing all the male
socialization I went through yeah
um shifting all my thoughts and emotions
forming new beliefs that were much more
supportive of
me within 3 months I went from Full
repression to wow I can't believe I can
do this yeah that's the power of
learning to shift your thoughts and
emotions and form new supportive ones I
used visioning
meditations in different
forms um I really got into
journaling for the first time in my life
and not so much writing down stuff and
making it pretty and putting it all no I
just typed in a Word document yeah all
the thoughts I had that were driving me
crazy I typed
them
and the power of that is five days later
I'd go back and read them holy I
don't want to think like that anymore no
wonder why I'm so miserable I don't want
to feel like that anymore
start rewriting that thought you can't
go from it's horrible to it's wonderful
in one step but gradual shifts of
changing the thought patterns right
that's what it takes and it's constant
work yeah well well so you we we we
discussed Joe dispenza you got into Joe
dispenza sounds like that was pretty
pretty pretty invaluable to you um I I
also excuse me I also stumbled into
you know on on my own journey of
discovering who I am and and and just
just the whole The Never Ending Journey
right um I stumbl across Joe despenza
and man it was some of the most profound
stuff not only does he have such great
meditations but his books his lectures
his appearances on podcast I feel like
you can listen to one of those and you
walk away just completely with a
different perspective on yourself and
other people and um it it really it
really opens the door to like um this
really fascinating and interesting thing
that everybody should everybody should
have feel permission to to dive deeply
into you know this Human Experience why
we're all here all of this so um what I
would love to ask you is when you first
started going to therapy when you first
started um speaking with a therapist out
of this you had all this you know I
think you said four and a half years of
or four and a half Decades of of
suppression I mean it must have been so
intense to actually get in there and
talk about it but was this all around
the same time did you start reading Joe
dispensa did you start journaling around
the same time and and kind of what
immediately seemed to help you feel kind
of free to to continue carrying
on the very first session was an intake
session it lasted for about an hour and
15 minutes or
so and I poured out everything it felt
totally
amazing just to say the words to
somebody and have them sit there and
talk with me about
it uh
um I had really put a lot of effort into
looking for a therapist one who I could
relate to one that I felt really
comfortable
with
and she was perfect in so many ways but
this her she didn't just listen to me
and well how do you feel about that and
all it was more why do you think that
what makes you believe that she
challenged everything I
said when I got up to leave that session
it was like wow I've actually talk to
somebody and she heard me and then as I
was leaving I turned to say goodbye and
she looked at me and she said what's
your
[Music]
name and I snapped back
Wendy I had picked that name in the
sixth grade she was the most popular
girl in my class blah blah blah if I
ever wanted if I could ever be a girl I
was going to be like
Wendy that was my name so I
snapped Stephanie crossed out my male
representative's name on my file and
wrote Wendy on my file from that day
forward I was Wendy to her that was
hugely profound she was the first person
in my entire life to hear me and really
accept me without any conditions as to
who I believe I
am by our next session we got
[Music]
into
boundaries because I had no boundaries
between myself and family at the
time so to do this you need to focus on
yourself you need to really focus on you
what you need need what's right for
you and that goes for a lot of Life
Changes you can't compromise well you
can I advise people not to compromise
their transitions or any major life
change to satisfy somebody else's
needs that compromises what you're doing
for
yourself so just focus on you and and
make
happened the other thing we got into was
the I brought in the visioning because I
she was taking me back into my hippie
days eching meditations all of the fun
stuff and yeah it was all good
and it was uh shortly thereafter that I
discovered Dr Joe I picked up his book
uh I actually bought it in audio
and listen to it because one of my
exercise routines is to go for a 3 to
Six Mile
Walk and I'd plug in my earbud earbuds
and listen to Dr Joe and it blew me away
and in Breaking the Habit of being
yourself chapters 7 and
8 that's so fundamental to everything
that I
did all the way through the first six
months
of um
2015 from January to June by the time I
got to
June there was no longer any
repression I was so done with my male
faximile and that life and I was ready
to leave everything behind and I
did and I couldn't have been happier my
wife at the time
was in March when I announ well I F late
of late February of 2015 I announced
that I was doing hormone replacement
therapy I was going to a clinic in
Philadelphia and start that and she said
well we didn't discuss it I said well
there's nothing to
discuss
boundaries this is something I need to
do for
me it's not open for discussion and she
said okay then we're getting a
divorce and I knew the answer to the
question I just said why and she said
you're going to become a woman I'm not a
lesbian I am not going to live with
somebody who lives as a woman and that's
it we're done I said Okay I I fully
understand and appreciate
it
and what I tell people that I'm coaching
who are going through this what the
they'll say well I love I love her I
don't want to leave
her
and my response has always been if she's
expressed the fact that she's not a
lesbian she doesn't want to be married
to somebody who's going to live as a
woman respect her
wishes honor
her and show her that you love her by
letting her
go that way
she also how would I feel I asked myself
this too how would I feel being a
heterosexual cisgender Woman married to
a man who now says he's a woman and
going to live as such yeah it's not
fair so that's a personal decision that
people have to make
but I it was about five five or six
years later my ex-wife now looked at me
and uh when I visited one day and she
said you know it's really good that you
left and did this all on your own you
never would have transitioned nearly as
well living with me I said yes I know
that thank you yeah you know we would
have been negotiating everything and I
wasn't going to live like that this is
something I had to do for me to be me
who I've always
SP right right okay so so how do
you I I I I also think about this this
area a lot as
well
the so much of our personality could
really be for others if we're not
careful and there's not anything
inherently wrong about you know we live
together in a community we live together
with other people and there's a little
bit of push and pull on that but
um if we're constantly just making sure
everyone else is okay everyone else
isn't uncomfortable if we're constantly
just kind of making sure we're keeping
the peace in the games of society but
it's betraying who we are and who we
feel we are I mean what's the what's the
point you know
where I I think about I I I I I like to
I like to contemplate lying in in in
being truthful um in my in my early 20s
I had I had my own lies I had lies that
I would realize after a while that I
would have to exert energy to keep
afloat right I can't just be who I am in
the moment because I might slip up and I
might say the wrong thing and uh I've
used the example excuse me a little bit
of a strange cough lately um I've used
the example of so like if you're being
unfaithful in a relationship and you're
having a great time or whatever or you
have been unfaithful whatever having a
great time you're enjoying you know your
lies are tucked away back there they
can't get to you whatever you think
having a good time with your wife or
your husband and then suddenly your
phone lights up from across the room and
then instantly you're pulled into your
own lies and your own fear you're oh
geez who Could That Be hopefully she
doesn't see it hopefully it's not
someone coming to like break my life
apart you know hopefully it's someone
not coming to expose me for who I am or
something and and your peace is
threatened because you're not being who
you are who you're not being truthful to
the people around you or to yourself and
um now I I love sharing it I love
talking about it
because the the peace that I feel to be
myself though though you know I I all
the things about me being human I didn't
you know heal everything wrong about me
or anything I'm still make mistakes and
I still all these things right but just
the fact that nobody could get me nobody
could come and sneak up on me my phone
can light up at any time with any person
in any relationship and there's no
dishonesty that can come and um Jordan
Peterson said uh he has one of his 12
rules for life thing and it's uh don't
hide things in the fog and and I always
love that it's like if you don't hide
things in lies in the fog they can't
come come and hurt you um and so I I
suppose I don't have like an exact
question for you but but do you resonate
with that do you resonate with like oh
being able to just there's nothing that
could get you does that feel I mean how
free does that feel to you well when I
first transitioned and started Living
fulltime in
um
2015 it was so
freeing I mean no longer any secret to
hide uh my ex-wife said to me that not
and my therapist and my psychiatrist
that she had me see also to um change up
all this I was on a whole collection of
scyth meds in order to suppress this I
found out I could go to psychiatrist and
just make up symptoms and they would
prescribe stuff and that was it as long
as I kept showing up they keep
prescribing that's another way in which
I suppressed all of this I never once
told them I did tell my psychiatrist
that I'd been seeing at my therapist's
assistance
and he wanted to send me for conversion
therapy this
is I was in Doylestown Pennsylvania in
2015 15 sure was in the 1920s and he
wanted me to go for conversion therapy
so I went to a new psychiatrist both my
therapist and my psychiatrist met my
male
faximile for the F uh when they first
met
me and I found out a couple years later
when I was talking with Stephanie both
uh the doctor and her were totally mind
blown at the intense personality change
immediately as soon as I became
myself it wasn't a gradual change it was
sudden and it just kept going CU I felt
so good it no longer having to hide
anything uh that graduated
into I played around at various times
with living stealth one of the things
that I had guilt about my entire life
was I married a
woman we were together for 40
years and that was a
lie I told it by Omission but it was
still a lie and that was a source of
profound guilt for most of my married
life so I did tell her about this in 20
in 19 19 78 we'd been married for a
while uh we already had a
family I couldn't take the the stress of
hiding
this so I wound up talking in my
sleep and that's when she uh demanded an
explanation woke me up I expected to be
divorced by morning the following
morning she said well as long as you
don't do anything about this will stay
together and that's the way it stayed
for the next uh 30 something
years period
so uh as far as the hiding and the
relief it just keeps going it keeps
getting better every day it's a new
experience the first couple of years
there are tons of new EXP experiences
things you've done for the first time as
yourself feeling
good where it's not different from
anybody else hiding
stuff is
um I moved into a city where I knew
nobody I'd never been here as an
adult I decided I just wanted to go
there and it's a growth experience to do
something like
that so
I spent much of 2024 socializing with
people in different venues around the
city and meeting people becoming
acquainted with
people in my particular situation now
that's a difficult thing to do and
stay and keep my secret that I'd
transitioned I what I like to do is let
people get to know me first as a person
person because once that happens when I
do bring out the fact that oh yeah I was
born
transgender I phrase it that way for for
two
reasons it emphasizes that this is how
this really happens we're born this way
it also takes the word that's out there
in the world choice that I chose to do
this it takes that off the
table and and the fact that they have
gotten to know me as a person and
actually talk with me and everything
else that diffuses the whole transgender
issue so when I come out to people it's
much less of a surprise depending on
where I
lived people would again walk away from
me no that's too much for me to handle
I'm out of here that kind of thing I did
get quite a bit of that but where I'm
where I'm living now it's just the
opposite people don't
care and it's cool and so in January
because I am getting more visible and
becoming more active I have my own
podcast now um I'm public speaking doing
other things and I'm out there I want my
friends to find out about me from me I
don't want to lie to them I don't want
to repeat that process
so they've gotten to know me so I came
out to
everybody and it's been
fine so I'm very fortunate in that
area a lot of people don't don't have
that because of where they live
right but yeah um we can really mess
ourselves up royally by hiding Our Truth
in who we are right so I intentionally
nowadays don't walk around with a
transgender pin or uh a flag or any of
that
I would rather have people have
conversations and get to know me and
then I'll tell them about it and we'll
go from there and majority of the time
I've made more friends doing that than
not right yeah yeah I mean a a simple
conversation can diffuse so much of what
we think we know you know just exactly
you know um I think
that I think
that what happens a lot Ian it does
happen with a with
some there's a version of I think when
it comes to like the
lgbtq um that whole world where there's
a hint of I want you to treat me
differently I want you to treat me
special I don't know if that's
necessarily true but it's something that
I I I feel a little bit or I hear a
little bit bit about it um and and I
think that it's like something on my end
that I like to just kind of glance over
I like to like I don't think at the
heart of what people are doing they
necessarily want to be treated special I
think they just want to be able to be
who they are and not have to explain
themselves all the time um something
like that um but I don't know where does
that resonate for you as far as cuz to
me when I talk to you I don't get the
feeling that you're trying to make me
treat you differently to me I think
you're just trying to live a human life
and express your truth and like like
that only has something to do with me if
I'm talking to you you know like um do
you do do you want people to treat you
differently do you want people to treat
you special absolutely not my whole
thing was I just wanted to blend into
society as any other woman and be
treated that way and that was all there
was to it 2018 and 2019
uh this was something that I explored I
had I had surgery after um I had surgery
in
so totally
female and I decided I have no idea what
my true sexual orientation really
is so I went and explored
that I found out I really am a
heterosexual female
and I had a great time dating men for
two years never revealing nobody ever
knew and it was all
fine as far as how I'm living now and
for most of us most of us really only
want to just be able to live our lives
openly
authentically and not have to worry
about
hiding uh as as I've said before and
I'll repeat this a lot of people feel
that if they're asked questions that now
they're put into a place where they're
having to explain and justify themselves
I've never felt that if somebody asks me
a question I take
it at face value for what it is they're
not trying to make judgments or anything
they just are curious and they ask the
question I'll answer it and have a
conversation with them about
it
but um I think on the part of
society um a lot of people in society
feel or
misinterpret what they're hearing to
think that we are needing to be treated
special because of who we are and that's
not the case at
all I don't believe most of the
community wants that we just want to
be just being just
living
and have people accept you for who you
are and what you are that's it it's that
simple
um sad
it gets demonized and made into a whole
bunch of other things but that's not the
transgender Community as a
whole
um there are a lot of people in the
community that feel like
victims because of
society I happen to know a lot about the
history of uh where we came from having
grown up in the
60s and um my childhood was in the 50s
so I'm older than
dirt but I'm so glad to have made it to
this point in my life it's a totally New
Perspective and that's what I want to
share with others in
society and help them change their
perspectives of people like myself
it's pretty much that simple yeah
um a lot of uh um a lot of people in
straight cisgender
society that that's the whole
heteronormative world that has been
embraced in this country ever since I've
been
around and so anything that falls
outside those boundar
uh is something very
different when I remember as a child as
a
teenager gay people
were
treated exactly the way transgender
people are treated
today it was not acceptable gay people
were
arrested people like myself in places
like San Francisco New York
City we were arrested thrown in jail
fined names in the newspapers that's the
way it
was and it was like that for gay people
pretty much into the mid to later
70s that's when their diagnosis changed
from a psychological thing that they
were born with and that they were you
know freak regarding and all of that in
society
and there was a lot of protests and you
know 19 June of 1969 was the Stonewall
riots in Manhattan in Greenwich Village
on Christopher
Street and that's when
the 20th century modernday gay movement
started was that June
and the first persons to throw bricks at
the New York City
cops weren't the gay people they were
the transsexuals and the drag
queens I was known as a transsexual
then and they were the ones that threw
the first bricks and started the
riot namely because they were sick and
tired of getting arrested thrown in jail
and paying outrageous fines
he so that's the history of where we've
come
from guess when the diagnostic code
changed for people like
me when
2012 oh wow that long that long
yeah I tried the transition in
[Music]
771 um Clockwork Orange had come out
um Wendy
Carlos a transsexual who had
transitioned did the sound track for cl
Clockwork
Orange I knew that she did it why
couldn't I well in those days if you
didn't have celebrity status and
financial means forget it
right and that was also when and I was I
had a psychiatrist who was actually
trying to help me in those days and he
took me as a case study patient to a
quarterly meeting of psychiatrists I'm
in a conference room in a hospital with
about 15 to 20 psychiatrists I'm talking
for no more than three or four minutes
the doctor stands up looks around the
room says I'll see you all next quarter
points at me and goes you're a freak you
should move to New York City and turn
tricks like the rest of
them in those days I had no idea what
the hell he was talking
about we didn't have cell phones we
didn't have social media there was no
connectivity between human life forms of
any kind other than newspapers and the
6:00 news that was
it no cable TV it was the stone ages
yeah
so fast forward into
today a lot of people even in my own
Community don't understand the history
and where we came from and the struggles
that people went through to get here and
the fact that we've only
had rights and re recognition by the
medical community for 13 years now
that's
it so we'll see where all of this goes
but um my mission as I said was to
humanize being born transgender and to
do as much as I can to change
perspectives that people have of people
like
myself well I mean you you bring me
optimism and I'm sure you bring many
others optimism so I I think you know as
much as as much as the media and in in
news and just you know the modern media
Zeitgeist for lack of a better term um
makes it seem like this makes it seem
like we're in the 60s or something but
um I I think on the other side we're all
going to be going oh we were a bit silly
about our reactions weren't we those are
just humans trying to exist like us oh
okay you
know and that's basically all it is it
really is yeah um
it's it is a profound life change it is
does fall outside the Norms of
society uh therapists uh that have
interviewed me um have also learned a
lot about what this is
about even
though even though we've had uh medical
and health care and therapeutic care and
all of that for 13 years
now that doesn't mean that the medical
community is prepared to deal with us
either uh there's a lot of really good
people out there who do and then there's
a lot who really have no comprehension
of this as well right and that will come
in
time um the way things are
now um they would like for us to hide
again go back to living underground in
major cities and all of that stuff the
way it used to be but that's not going
to happen anymore no you shouldn't
suppress who you are no absolutely
not
and I know I'm not everybody's cup of
tea and there are a lot lot of people
out there that wouldn't want anything to
do with
me uh for their own personal reasons and
I'm okay with
that but uh I have I have met some
really wonderful people and had some
really great conversations and made some
really good
friends all of whom I still keep in
touch
withh it's it's been a really
fascinating and interesting Journey
so I have I have two questionss that
come to mind at once um I'll give you
the challenge of trying to intertwine
them uh uh firstly I think what what is
it about other people like our initial
I'm thinking about that guy in that
meeting like what is it that was so
challenging to him that he felt like no
I going to call this person a freak and
walk out like what I I feel like somehow
something about you expressing like
triggered something within him um you
know it's kind of the same thing that
happens when I notice if I if I casually
bring up death like death is something
that I don't it's not a big deal I've
spent a lot of time thinking about it I
enjoy philosophy and I just think
something I contemplate a lot but I'll
notice I'll mention it in you know a
casual conversation and I'll just
completely lose someone's interest or
they're like I don't want to talk about
death I don't want you know they just
get super uncomfortable and they like
change the subject and I got to notice
oh okay like things that I think about
aren't necessarily at the Forefront of
of what everyone else is thinking about
so um I'm curious about what you think
there you know what what lies Bey behind
that um initial reaction like that and
then um also my second question to uh
give you the challenge of intertwining
them is
um
what someone who notices that they're in
that position someone who maybe is like
maybe they have someone that they love
and they're whatever for whatever reason
they're listening to this conversation
and they're realizing man I I think my
reaction was kind of like that I think I
think uh I didn't have the best response
cuz I was so caught off guard when
someone brought that up to me
that um I I turned my back on them when
when they they were asking to be seen
you know and so how do I how do I
commend with that so what lies Beyond
well what lies behind that reaction and
then if someone realizes that maybe they
were in that boat or they're still in
that boat um what's kind of a good next
step for them to to contemplate it and
maybe um reach out to that friend or
something even
well it it really all goes back to the
whole structure of our heteronormative
society
um and people are gravitating toward
that right now with there's only men
there's only women you're born that way
that's the way you stay that's the way
it's always been that's the way it will
always be that's their
mindset that's their belief
system someone like
myself and
the vast majority of the community is
totally outside that
Norm and they can't possibly live and
accept that because it's outside their
whole belief
systems uh Law of Attraction and beliefs
you can't live outside your
beliefs so being open to a new
perspective means that you have to start
questioning what you yourself
believe in order to even hear this
person who's saying I just want to be
me in order to hear that person accept
that person for who they
are a person that believes that strongly
in the whole heteronormative society
structure and belief system has to begin
to question that you throw on top of
it uh religious
beliefs that gets even more profoundly
difficult to change that person's
perspectives they have they have to
begin to be open to changes themselves
and my sign back there change is good
yeah I in my previous
life change was always very
difficult we don't like change change is
risk change
is something that is a lot of people are
afraid
of
and all the the last 10 years of
self-discovery and really digging into
who I am as a human being and
learning things about the human mind and
thoughts and
beliefs I've come to really Embrace
change change is good it really is and
it can be it can be challenging but it's
also exciting it's different and I've
come to also believe that life is about
possibility and it's our
beliefs and all the thoughts that we
carry that support those beliefs that
will either mask what is possible for us
or completely hide it from our view and
make us believe that it's totally
impossible
um so in order for somebody who is not
willing
to hear about someone like myself it's
not me it's them and it's their belief
structure and their inability or
unwillingness and refusal to
change even part a part of their belief
system to allow this to come into
it yeah I feel like people
they I mean we get stuck to our
identities don't we you know uh oh yeah
I feel if if if you don't have a
understanding that you're much more
than just who you are in society or you
know you're much more than just the
typical you know your job you're you're
you're a father you're a mother you're a
construction worker you're you're these
things I mean you're you're also those
but paradoxically you're you know the
expression of Consciousness itself and
all that cool stuff
too um yeah I think that challenging
that stuff is is pretty heavy for people
and uh I think their initial reactions
when they're like that it kind of
exposes them of oh you've never
challenged the things that you were
taught as a child like that that could
be an issue a real issue yes a lot of
people are not open to uh uh changing
their belief
structures that's just such a scary
thing to do and
a lot of uh uh I was one of them one of
those guys out there living my life
um was very unhappy behind the scenes
and quite miserable but just toughed it
all the way through
and my identity was my
work that's how I got through true I
became this computer person then I
became this consultant
person that went out and did did did
things at different corporations and all
of that that was my identity was my work
my job my
career
and a lot of us get totally wrapped up
in that and we don't see who else we are
I was busy repressing ing who I really
was and so it made grabbing on to that
even much tighter much more forcefully
and yeah that's who I am
yeah but that really wasn't yeah yeah
what what a crazy amount of pressure to
put on a job oh yeah yeah complete me
tell me exactly who I am entirely yeah
that's that's heavy you know yeah that's
nice to set it down but uh I've really
enjoyed uh uh going through learning all
of these things about myself I've uh
and I'm I've I've done a lot of work on
my own emotionally mentally and all of
that and I've also hired people to help
me because there are things that you do
need guidance with and all of that and
once once once doing that yeah I can
take another step
forward I still I still have I still had
uh limiting
beliefs that I'd formed in childhood
that were still hanging around there I'd
overcome the majority of
them but they were still there and every
time I thought about public
speaking they would they would really
kick in and say nope you can't do that
that's not safe and
so and that was a very deep situational
subconscious fear and belief that I was
holding on to I got help
hypnotherapist and we've broken through
and it's all good yeah hear you on
podcast you know you're talking you're
sharing you're definitely not afraid of
public speaking now so it's amazing but
even where I say it's situational
um the idea
of I spoke about about eight or 10 times
in
Manhattan at different events and
different
situations and both at NYU at the Out
Foundation and at a couple of other
places and I enjoyed it but I hadn't
done it
in
years uh 2019 was the last year that I
ever did did that and so the thought of
starting up doing that
again even after sitting in front of the
camera talking with people like you and
having these conversations the idea of
standing in front of a live
audience
whoa I got some help we're getting
through it I'm good
I I actually joined uh Toast Master in
January
to it's a uh organization it's a
national or actually Global
organization uh that uh helps people
become better public speakers oh
brilliant I love that yeah it's been
around for forever last century it was
here and uh I got in front of my uh uh
first meeting and I decided okay I have
no idea what I'm going to say I gave up
one of the other things I learned about
myself was I'm very much sacral I go by
how things
feel as opposed to what I think I was
raised to be this everything has to be
logical laid out planned blah blah blah
blah
blah in 2015 I gave that up Jacob I
totally gave that up I have no idea what
it would be like to live as a woman I
don't even know if I'll like it but I
got to try it and see where it
goes and that's what I did and I just
decided I'm going to go by how it
feels uh the last 6 months of
2023 uh I put my business on hold my
coaching business on hold focused on
emptying the family house and selling it
took me months done gone during that
entire process my ex-wife was asking me
well where are you going to live I don't
know well when are you going to figure
that out said after I'm done with all of
this I'm sure the universe will guide me
in some direction there will be a path
that opens up for me and that's when I
usually get told of you're really out
there you belong in California I've been
told that too
yeah yeah that that's a sentence that
happens in Texas often I hear you so uh
I
um and it really did happen um two of uh
uh one of my LinkedIn connections said
Wendy if you're considering uh moving
back to New England and you would be
open to Rhode Island reach out to this
person she's a realtor she'll help
you and I've been living for 3 weeks in
a hotel and had no clue where I was
going to
go I followed up with that I made a
contact we had a zoom connection next
thing I know I'm in Rhode Island
standing in front of an apartment
building with the
realtor and the rest of is history yeah
yeah so so what you're saying is you
began trusting your gut instead of
overthinking things over the last 10
years totally so when I went to Toast
Masters for the first time they said oh
you can introduce yourself now and and
um it's that part of the meeting and uh
you can just stay at your seat well no
there's about somewhere in the
neighborhood of 20 25 people in the room
I got up in front introduced myself I
said hi I'm Wendy Cole I was born
transgender and I
paused and watched the facial
expressions they couldn't have been
nicer I explained why I was there that I
want to improve my speaking I've done a
approximately 40 podcasts I'm uh getting
into public speaking more
and I'm out there and then I ended with
I'm an open book you can ask me anything
you want to and absolutely nothing's off
limits and that includes all of you that
was my first
meeting and that felt so good it was
freeing
yeah I wasn't hiding I wasn't making
excuses I wasn't wasn't
pretending and I was just
me freedom to be yourself exactly what a
gift okay well so I want to ask I want
to dive a little bit more into uh I mean
you you you mentioned hypnotism um
hypnotherapy I did a little bit of that
myself actually when I was kind of uh
years ago I was working through just my
own trauma depression just for me just
severe things that happened in childhood
that um I didn't know how to deal with
you know cuz I was just a
kid later in life I had to I had to read
some books and I had to listen to some
podcasts and I had to deal with these
things you know um and one of the things
that honestly helped me was was Hypno
hypnosis hypnotherapy um I actually had
like this crazy I don't know if you had
any um uh I don't know if you had any
sort of like mystical experiences that
that you're willing to share about if
that was of any part of your journey but
for me I was a I was doing a ton of
breath work I was doing a ton of yoga I
was smoking a lot of cannabis so that's
obviously a huge part of it but um I was
I was just I was in my basement just
unpacking I'm just like whatever's not
me I'm ripping it out you know I was
like I mean I was kind of caught up
trying to destroy my ego at the moment I
didn't realize that I I could hug my ego
and all that but um I uh I uh so I did
hypn hypnosis and I would just find
random stuff on YouTube I'd find
different um hypnotherapy people i' just
kind of listen to their things and I
would just give into it just try it out
you know um obvious I wouldn't you know
you're giving someone permission to dive
deep into your mind so you want to do
some vetting and make sure that you you
feel intuitively good about what that
person is teaching and saying whatnot
but uh man I had uh I had this moment
where I I kind of like envisioned after
my my hypnosis I had for one an
experience of being The Color Purple I
know that's crazy but I was like I
became the color purple I was like smoke
and water at the same time and just
really gave in to being the color purple
very healing very uh uh I felt really
really great afterwards and then within
minutes I had a vision of my teenage
self was there and I was hugging my
teenage self and saying thank you for
everything you did but I got it from
here and I mean it was it's like a
profound moment of my life and I think
it probably always will be and um it it
was huge it was so healing for me it
helped me understand myself I was able
to really understand more about myself
the following months afterwards and
everything so um just I I don't know I
kind of want to ask you if you had any
experiences of that similarity and if
hypnosis or um I mean even if if you
want to talk about it even if you had
any experiences with psychedelics in in
in that world that might have helped you
um there's my rambling question
I'll love it um as far uh one of the
things that I got very good at from the
beginning in 2015
was meditating and getting into more of
that Theta state of
mind and so I was able to uh go through
and work on a lot of the things that my
therapist was telling me that I needed
to change by doing
that
um I had uh I had always been fascinated
with psychedelics as a kid I I in one in
one summer I I think it was my sophomore
between my sophore and junior year high
school or somewhere along there I
discovered Bob Dylan The Grateful deed
and um Jefferson
Airplane and I read all about the
Psychedelic scene in California and
everything that was going on with Ken
kiry and the Mary pranksters and all of
that stuff and their bus tours doing
acid and I was thinking oh my God maybe
acid would fix
me um I that got me into a lot of
trouble because I never I never tried
acid then but I did uh write a paper in
high school about it and uh the wonders
of psychedelics and T Timothy liry and
the whole California scene and
everything well my parents were
concerned that I you know I told them
already that I was a girl now you write
a paper and you're a drug addict and we
get called into the high school yeah
you're quoting Timothy ly uh oh yeah
back then that must have been intense
that was intense in those
days but
uh I have tried
acid um I survived the 80s on pot vast
quantities that was another way in which
I pressed
everything that and music music has been
my
lifeblood from my early teens all the
way through it makes me happy it
distracts my mind it keeps me energized
and there's so many things in a lot of
the rock bands that I can relate to and
I became a dead
head
so but um
over the last 10 years I focused more on
the meditative States getting into that
Theta State and really digging in there
and my hypnotherapist tells me that
she's amazed at how quickly I can go
into that state well I've been
practicing and as Dr Joe says when you
get in there you can start digging
around in your own mind and changing
those thought pth patterns and rewiring
your
brain
and I thoroughly believe in that I've
had those very profound experiences one
of the other ways in which I meditate is
while I'm
walking the physical
activity the earbuds and the music
cranked I can zone out and be in a
totally different place I'm aware of my
surround ings
but I'm consciously processing a lot of
other stuff that's going on
mhm and that's how I've been doing a lot
of my shifting of my beliefs and really
expanding my mind to
include doing other things and other
possibilities
um yes it it's a profound experience
with a lot of doing this kind of work on
yourself
and with the hypnotherapy it it does
work and it helped me I found that
really fascinating what you said you
learn you found that you could actually
hug your teenage self oh it was huge too
it was yes I couldn't even put it in
words how helpful that was for me yes
and recently that's what I've gone
through with letting
my 5-year-old 10-year-old 15-year-old
self and my 20-some self
know hey I'm a different person today
thank you for doing what you did you
kept me
safe you kept
me from doing all kinds of things that I
could have done to
myself and suicidal ideation was one of
them MH So yeah thank you for not
killing me making me a drug addict or an
alcoholic yeah yay
yeah for yeah thank you for the person I
had to be you
know yeah you got me to where I am today
and for that I'm eternally
grateful yeah oh I love Leonard Skinner
too yeah why do you bring that in why do
you mention that I think I saw that on
your back wall
oh oh junkyard I'm sorry junkyard oh no
I I was like what what a what
correlation I saw the
Ard and I immediately that popped into
my head it it is it's it's a my secret
correlation no I got my little junkyard
love poster back there but I do like
Lear scner too um okay well
so I want to chime into say someone's
listening and they are transgender but
they're not in a place where they're
that's who who they're living as
outwardly
[Music]
um what what's obviously they got to
find the next step that makes sense for
them
right what what would you encourage
though you know say someone I'm sure you
probably have this experience I'm say
someone messages you directly and says
hey you know I'm comfortable talking
about this with you but I wouldn't want
everybody else to know what I'm telling
you here's what I've got going on what
what is like the next best step what is
something that is healing what is
something that is in the right direction
for them um what is something that I
suppose like what would your response be
would it be hey you know maybe you
should try try out meditation um start
talking to a therapist um you know try
read these books check out these YouTube
videos what what is kind of your first
initial I mean now we have your your
podcast which is a great great uh tool
for them you could send them but what
would be your response to them um one of
the things that I know personally I
didn't have and most people especially
uh very early stages in this a complete
lack of self-acceptance
and that again stems from the beliefs
that we
hold so what I would encourage
is uh really start working
on see a therapist but they have to be a
therapist who understand
this at least to some degree and that
people who have who are born this way
actually have no self-acceptance
whatsoever of who they are they're too
busy repressing
it
and so I would want them to actually
make sure they see a therapist and a
therapist is one of the things that you
need in order to go for any further
treatments with surgeries and things
like that
anyway
but I would be more than happy to talk
with
them about what it takes to change your
internal belief system
and basically start reconstructing who
you are to where you have supportive
thoughts going through your mind all day
all day long every day
there's all these doubts fears shame
guilt all of those things are swirling
in people's minds every day who are
living and not not expressing who they
truly
are and it can affect every aspect of
their
lives and it's
actually there's a belief in the
community that transition is difficult
and takes a long time
and my statement to that is if that's
what you believe that's exactly how it
will be it will be difficult and it will
take a long time it doesn't have
to change your thought patterns and
that's something I'm particularly good
at helping them do change the thought
patterns change how you feel about
yourself
and once you gradually start shifting
those thoughts and those
emotions invariably people begin to see
what's possible for them and they
actually will start taking
steps forward in my coaching work uh
especially my one-on-one
work we meet weekly they get homework
every
week I expect to talk about the homework
the following week I hold them
accountable this is not a game we're
going through this if you're committed
to yourself to make these changes and to
do what you need to do I can help
and one of the things that I've seen
work beautifully is someone who's seeing
a therapist and working with me at the
same time
they just take off and it becomes fun it
becomes easy and they actually enjoy it
and I tell people at the when you're on
the other side of
this there's nothing but joy for
you it's F you're finally
free and it's a very uh worthwhile
experience to go through it really is
it's it does turn your life inside out
and upside down to say the least yeah I
had one client who um uh had a bunch of
guy friends and they rode
motorcycles and I said well once you do
this they're kind of
[Music]
gone they're probably going to go away
from
you but you're going to meet other
people and
uh I found in my own experience
I found that uh women were far more
accepting of me than
men by far most uh heterosexual men
would look and go I don't
know and off they'd go that would be the
end but
um uh women much more
accepting and much more open to uh
conversation and Lear learning and all
of that and
then all of my gay
friends men and women very open very
accepting and surprisingly didn't
understand this any better than straight
people
do
it's but
yeah changing your thoughts changing
your feelings changing your emotions and
getting help to do do that is the
Cornerstone of being able to find
self-acceptance and then deconstructing
all the male socialization or female
socialization depending which way you're
going deconstructing all that
socialization and building it back
up to match your authentic
self those are keys
and for people that
are one of the things I've noticed too
is people that are living
fulltime but haven't done the internal
work to change their thought patterns
and change who they are internally done
the mental
work
um they
have they live in a different situation
than I do they live with uh uh being
afraid most of the
time
and their fear is not so much from
outside as it's still inside in their
own mind they think of themselves as
being different from everybody
else because of how they were born with
this
transgender uh
situation and they feel and hold on to
that sense of
difference that's something that needs
to go
too
[Music]
um I've had people tell me well I'm
getting misgendered all the time out in
public running errands doing this doing
that and I look at them we're on zoom
and I'm looking at them and I'm going oh
you look
fine and then I'll ask them I'll say to
them like this
jacob what are you thinking when you're
out in
public how are you feeling about
yourself what's going through your mind
tell me and they'll ramble on a little
bit and then I'll hear the word well I'm
a trans woman so and I go
stop you just called yourself a trans
woman I understand that you put a label
on yourself
why did you go through all of this work
and completely turn your life upside
down and inside out to be a transom or
to be the woman you've always
been oh lose the word
trans you're not being dis disloyal to
the
community you're being loyal to
yourself I always say I was born
transgender I own that and I am part of
the
community but I don't
identify as anything else other than a
female as a woman that's
it so when I'm out in public that's the
energy I'm putting
out when people engage with me it's a
perfectly normal conversation they're
having I'll talk with people in the
supermarket about items they're
selecting and stuff like that you know
I've had occasions with or I'll go into
a bar and there's only one seat and it's
between two guys and I actually had this
happen they're both on their phones well
I go to a bar to have conversations not
necessarily to get drunk or anything
just to have conversation with people
and see
people I sat down boom I started a
conversation with the guy on the left
left just started a
conversation dragged the guy on my right
into the same conversation and next
thing I know I've got the bartender
involved too we're having a great time
everybody put their phones down and it
was a good
time but if that's the energy you as a
transgender individual are putting out
into the world that's how people are
going to receive you if you are putting
out there I'm different
I'm a transom I'm um
afraid of everybody in society
M people are not going to know that
you're transgender and I'll tell tell
this to them all the time they're not
going to know
that what they're going to know and what
they're going to sense is there's this
other energy about you that's very
different they might pick up on the fear
they might pick up on the anxiety but
they're going to sense it and that's
going to color their relationship with
you we're all about energy
MH and if that's what you're putting out
that's how they're going to see you and
then they're going to realize okay yeah
there is something different about you
and that's when they might pick up on
some Quee that says
oh sir and you get misgendered
it's that
simple as I tell everybody that I've
ever worked
with your gender identity is formed
instinctively within 5 Seconds of
someone seeing you or
less from that point forward it's up to
you not to confuse them and that's why I
teach gender mannerisms and
behaviors right all in this process it
all comes together we are a total our
bodies and our minds are a total system
and how they work together and get us
through the world in everyday life works
as a system yeah yeah it and one part of
that system can't be screwed
up yeah because it's like a I like to
say you can lie just not to yourself you
know there there is this and and even
when we do lie externally if we know
that there's a lie there's a little bit
of a frequency that other people are
like huh that feels strange so when
you're able to just that's the energy
yeah yeah and people pick up on that and
then you're kind of like defending
something you weren't even trying to
like put out into the world you know
right so okay so I I I really love the
word awareness there's this book called
uh I literally think it's actually just
called awareness it's by Anthony Deo
Dello or whatever but uh it was so good
for me when I read it back in the day I
love it I re revisit it from time to
time but um it basically talks about
it's just kind of the profound
importance of initial awareness of like
when you are at that bar when you are
talking to people like what is your
thought process like there is this whole
world out here and like I'm I'm a person
in this bar in this city and I'm talking
to this person and they're wearing a red
shirt and there's all that but like what
is your mind saying inside as you're in
there what's going on with that and like
the importance of bringing awareness to
that so you can really work with what's
actually going on so does that spark
anything for you the the word awareness
and and how important it is I believe in
three things that are fundamental to
everything
self-awareness that's that's huge and
has to be there first and
foremost self-acceptance
that's
key and if you have those two things and
you're working on your thoughts and
emotions and to be more supportive of
you as a human being you might actually
start to discover you have
self-love I can honestly say until 10
years ago I had none I hated myself I
hated who I was I hated everything about
my
life was I aware oh yeah very
aware and
and but self-acceptance I had
none and self-love
zero those three things are
crucial to having a healthy well
adjusted mental Outlook as any human
being
would so it's beyond just the awareness
so people get the awareness and then
they got to take another step
yeah yeah okay so what so self-love
self-acceptance what are your what are
your base level standards for those if
someone's like you know that's where
they need to start it's something they
can start working on what's something
that someone could do if they're they're
noticing they're in a spot right now
that they're like okay I need to work on
my self- Lov my self-acceptance what
what are some actionable steps they can
take in terms of self-acceptance
um Bas make sure that self-awareness is
there otherwise you'll never find
self-acceptance awareness is very
fundamental as a human being and you're
absolutely right to bring that
up and in terms of uh working on
self-acceptance
that again starts within the human mind
digging in there to actually change your
thoughts and
beliefs um
when I'm working with someone I'll put
them through um I'll try different forms
of journaling some people don't like to
write don't like to type whatever you
know record it record your
thoughts anything that will get you to
actually record how you're feeling how
you're thinking at that moment you know
like oh my life is total I just
can't believe I'm doing all of this and
I can't believe I was born this way and
all record all of that crap write it
down put it someplace look at it
later and keep looking at it is that
what you want when you make up your mind
that you want to change that that's when
you can begin to
actually do what Dr Joe says is rewiring
your
brain and that rewiring process
takes about three months worth of
concerted effort
in most cases to completely
shift what you're thinking and that will
change everything about your
self-acceptance
and self-love is something that
gradually comes in
time can take anywhere from
um well I would say easily within about
uh six months of work
that's what I've seen in people that
I've worked
with it's it's it's not overnight but uh
the self-love does come and it's totally
dependent on self-acceptance and
self-awareness yeah and so so is it
worth it would you say six months seems
like a long time Wendy oh no compared to
a lifetime forget it it's nothing
seriously right it's nothing
yeah and it's amazing how fast even uh
the three months of work can
go um my main one-on-one coaching
program is 16 weeks by
Design so that I have the 13 weeks in
there to actually help someone get
through that whole process and in
addition to the mental work the mindset
work the shifting of everything all of
that that when I start adding in all of
the other steps and things that they
need to do this to
survive um a road map of all the things
that you need to go
through um which can be quite
daunting but the benefit of it is is you
get to check things off and say you're
going through a uh difficult time where
you're a little bit kind of weirded out
by things that are happening and you
know all of that you can go back and
look at this road map and say oh these
are all the things I've already done
progress yeah yeah
and after every session two I like to
have people especially those who are um
still not comfortable being out in
public do life
tests go someplace as your authentic
self do something
be exposed to people let people see
you
and one little life test after
another it begins to work you begin to
see that oh
yeah I went one of the things I did is I
went pretend grocery
shopping after therapy I went to the
supermarket and I pushed a card around
for a while love did any pay any
attention to me
no I was just another woman pushing a
shopping cart through a supermarket cool
I can do
this and I did another one where uh I
said to Stephanie I'm going to stop for
coffee at Starbucks when it was Dunkin
Donuts and it was a Dunkin Donuts that
didn't have a drive-thru cuz drive-thru
would be cheating yeah yeah I want to
stand in line
the first time I tried it I parked the
car I shut off the engine I couldn't
open the door Jacob I could not get out
of the car dang it I walked into
therapy I looked at her and I said I
failed cuz IID told her the week before
I was going to stop for coffee she
looked at me and said no you didn't
you'll do it when you're ready mhm that
was a huge lesson
I thought about it the next uh all the
way through the therapy session I told
her at the end I said I'm doing it next
week I did more meditations I did more
visioning I uh really put some effort
into shifting my own beliefs that I
could do
this the next week I shut off the car I
open the door yeah it
opens I
and it was the you know again it was
like January no was in February or so
and yeah I'm wearing a dress I'm wearing
heels bum B bum you know they hear all
this going across the parking lot I walk
in I open the door and there's a line
now I get in the
line and so far nobody's paying any
attention to me everything's
cool two local police officers walk in
and they're standing behind
me this
triggered New York State and New York
City
1970s where I would be arrested right by
these two
cops and I go H
stop
no that's this is different you're a
different person this is a different
time and place there just here for
coffee like you are I actually turned
smiled and said
hi and oh hi that was it yeah that's
all I went I paid for my coffee I that
was the first time I actually had the
experience of jug juggling a wallet a
purse and everything else while I was
took this these are first time things
that that you don't think
of but
and I made it over to the place where I
put the uh cream and the sugar in and
all of that stuff and I'm looking around
is anybody paying attention to me
no I walked into therapy did it this
week yep you're ready and that was
it I just knew that this was how it was
going to
be and it doesn't take that long to get
there um I've put a lot of stuff on my
YouTube channel and now um my website
has all my podcast interviews in my blog
all organized in there great and anybody
who hears this uh today is more than
welcome to dig around listen learn
whatever I don't hide a thing I put all
of my coaching stuff into that
and it all works yeah well I will
definitely I'm going to include the
links to all those things um your link
tree and whatever will lead them to all
of your work um so anybody listening
right now please there's links below go
click on those and uh just even if
you're not wanting to listen to it right
at this moment go hit subscribe and
follow and all that on our page so it
starts coming up in your algorithm so
you know maybe when you're in a a
different headp space or it's something
that sounds interesting to you you want
to explore more it comes up on your feed
so I would like to encourage everybody
to do that um um Wendy we are getting up
here in time um I do want to I do want
to get I've enjoyed our conversation a
lot absolutely me too I I mean I really
enjoyed our phone conversation just a
couple weeks ago I feel like I learned
so much about you and um it was really
nice to just just hear you express
yourself and hear about your journey and
um just just humanize you you know I
love that um so I've really had a great
time um I do want to send us off with a
little bit of a bow tie
um okay how do I phrase this I
I used to ask this question at the end
of the podcast like what does the world
need more of right now and it's such an
open question I feel like that it's it
kind of Narrows you into like we need
love this is the junkyard love podcast
but um with
today's like like really right now you
know the middle of uh March
2025 keeping in mind everything that's
going on bringing in your entire history
of who you are you've lived how however
many years on this planet bringing all
it into the present
moment what's useful for people to hear
right
now wow what's useful for
people I would have to say it's all
about
possibilities people
are just need to be open to different
possibilities and different ways
of seeing
things
um we need to break loose from all the
confines of our
past um and a lot of the social norms
that we
have uh need to really shift and
change and the only way that that can
happen is if people become more open to
what is
possible and learn to embrace that yeah
I think that is my new favorite word for
the day that was so perfect possibility
I think that is an excellent
answer okay well I'm Gonna Let You Go
Wendy I uh I want to thank you again for
your time I want to thank you for just
everything you're doing just for other
people like you you know everything
you're doing for for the education of
just all of our humanity and um thank
you for your bravery really okay and one
of the links that I will send you is the
link to uh for people basically
cisgender straight or gay
people who are interested in learning
more directly and having open
conversations of forming this
community we meet we'll meet on Zoom
monthly uh I put out a newsletter for
the community and it's associated with
the podcast demystifying the transgender
journey and the whole purpose of this uh
Community is to inform people help
people have a framework for
comprehending the transgender
world
and uh hopefully have and that for a
network of informed allies because one
of the
things we will we as PE transgender
people will not succeed in existing in
society without
allies it's allies that help the gay
community it's going to be allies that
help the transgender Community
become more part of society it will take
time but I'm doing my
part to actually try to make a
difference and help people have a
framework for comprehension and changing
perspectives and seeing what's possible
seeing what's possible indeed
possibility okay excuse me well thank
you so much uh that's my pitch for the
community too no it's a great one and I
love it and I'm glad that you shared it
um yeah so all those links will be below
Explore More of Wendy I appreciate
everybody tuning in to the junk out love
podcast I hope everyone has a beautiful
rest of your day if you have not
stretched or drank any water today
you're out of your mind you need to do
both stretch I always have to remind
everybody those two things oh absolutely
those are clear or I would say I'll add
a third because I'm so with you on this
one of my favorite things ever is go for
a walk and listen to an audio book I I
couldn't be in more agreement with you
on that I that is one of my favorite
things ever so stretch drink water go
for a walk check out Wendy's links below
and uh y Wendy you have a good day thank
you so much you too thank you I'll be in
touch all right you have a good day see
you bye bye
[Music]
everybody knowledge is
power reality
is junkyard love podcast